<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: social | Socialeyes Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/blog/categories/social/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-03-17T20:55:58-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Socialeyes]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How do we socialize?]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/blog/2014/08/26/how-do-we-socialize/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-26T05:30:55-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/blog/2014/08/26/how-do-we-socialize</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Socializing is in our nature. While the very basics of how we interact such as <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Handshake">handshaking</a> are both widespread and ages old, the specifics has always been in flux. Social occasions that our interactions revolve around, change across different ages and cultures.</p>

<!-- more -->




<p style="text-align:center">
<img src="/images/post/handshake.jpg" title="right" >
</p>


<p>Perhaps the more radical changes are to do with the medium of our social interactions. The advent of the world wide web and mobile devices has given us tools that allow us to communicate in ways we could only imagine. The trend has been to increase the amount of people we can interact with.</p>

<p>Socialeyes is our take on how people could interact today. Our focus is to help our users socialize with their friends in real life rather than a horde of acquaintances online.
We want our users to shake hands.</p>

<p>Socialeyes helps people share what they are in the mood for, so that they could meet on the fly.</p>

<p>We have gathered some information directly from our database to see how do people use Socialeyes to meet up;</p>

<h2>Most social day of week</h2>

<p>Of course it&rsquo;s Saturday! Are we surprised? No! Saturday and Sunday are given as weekend in all working societies.
As a result %53 of the social gathering requests made in weekends. Wednesday is the most social working day in a week.
I guess we get a little bit overwhelmed with work and school in the middle of the week, we would like to meet with our beloved ones.</p>

<h2>Most social hours of the day</h2>

<p>Mostly we love to get together when the sun is at the top. %26 of the meeting requests are posted between 11:00AM to 01:00PM.
When we have a lunch break at the office or a little bit time between the classes in the school all we can think of is meeting with friends.
The socializing requests continue with lowering percentages until 09:00PM.</p>

<h2>Most popular social activities</h2>

<p>For certain, we most love to grab a coffee, chilling with friends  with a little bit chit chat.
Approximately, %38 of the socializing requests are drinking coffee, chatting and chilling with friends.
We can clearly see listening to music is one of the indispensable activities of all the time with %13.5 ratio. (I was listening to <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7jr1uk2SvbY">http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7jr1uk2SvbY</a> while I am writing this blog post.)</p>

<h2>Most social areas of the world</h2>

<p>Socialeyes is used in United States by far the most with nearly %60 usage. The Middle East and Asia comes the second. Europe, Africa and South America are in the bottom of the list with least usage,
whether these continents need no socializing tool or no social at all. Come on! give Socialeyes a shot, we aim to make you meet with your friends easily.</p>

<p>Here we have prepared an infographic with many more details than described above. Please check it out for more details!</p>

<script id="infogram_0_how-do-we-socialize" src="//e.infogr.am/js/embed.js" type="text/javascript"></script>


<div style="width:100%;border-top:1px solid #acacac;padding-top:3px;font-family:Arial;font-size:10px;text-align:center;"><a target="_blank" href="//infogr.am/how-do-we-socialize" style="color:#acacac;text-decoration:none;">How do we Socıalıze</a> | <a style="color:#acacac;text-decoration:none;" href="//infogr.am" target="_blank">Create Infographics</a></div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hey Facebook! This is What We Want]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/blog/2014/08/25/hey-facebook-this-is-what-we-want/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-25T11:14:43-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/blog/2014/08/25/hey-facebook-this-is-what-we-want</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There are times when being on Facebook is a painful experience. We spend about 30 mins daily on average on Facebook. I am pretty sure there have been times when you got tired of browsing only because of some small details that should have been different to make your experience a better one. I feel that if Facebook made some minor changes in its App/Web Page, it would be a beter experience for the user.</p>

<p style="text-align:center">
<img src="/images/post/facebook.jpg">
</p>




<!-- more -->


<p>Here are some of the main ones:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Just show me the most recent posts</p></li>
<li><p>When a friend makes a comment about a post, this should not bring the post to the top of the feed again. Just bring me the most recent ones. I am not interested in the same post that I saw 3 hours ago. This is only okay if someone has mentioned me.</p></li>
<li><p>I do not care if someone has liked another post. Seeing other people liked someone else’s post prevents me from liking more stuff on Facebook. If you are an Instagram and Facebook user at the same time, you can see the clearest proof of this. Simply post the same photo to both of your accounts simultaneously. Although you have more friends on Facebook the likes you will receive on Instagram will be more than Facebook. I guarantee.</p></li>
<li><p>You should do a better job with notifications. The goal is to keep connected. Let me know when someone has commented on my post or liked my things etc.</p></li>
<li><p>For God’s sake put an end to this Facebook Messenger bu&hellip;hit. If I want to use a different app to text to my friends I have Whatsapp! (Remember the time you paid $19,000,000,000?) Stop forcing me to leave the app.</p></li>
<li><p>Facebook is not good enough for my face-to-face socializing needs. Try to come up with better product/app so that people do not only socialize virtually but also get out and meet in real life. Pay attention to startups like Socialeyes that concentrate on these sorts of problems. See them as a potential target for acquiring and making a better product.</p></li>
<li><p>Make your privacy settings easier. It is really painful to figure out each one of them and change them.</p></li>
<li><p>I may not want to be tagged in a photo. Get my permission first. Although you offer this feature, when a friend tags me, it appears on everyone&rsquo;s news feed anyway. Come up with a better privacy feature to solve this problem.</p></li>
</ul>


<p>Enough criticism. Special thanks to Mark Zuckerberg for the whole ALS ice bucket thing. If it wasn’t for him, this movement may not have reached to so many people around the world. Good job Mark!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Are People Really Getting Tired of Social Networks?]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/blog/2014/08/11/are-people-really-getting-tired-of-social-networks/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-11T06:08:10-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/blog/2014/08/11/are-people-really-getting-tired-of-social-networks</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A year ago I was out of a meeting and starting walking in a very busy district in the city. It was about lunch time and I was starving. I wanted to grab a bite but did not want to do it alone. So I called a friend of mine hoping he would be somewhere nearby. He wasn’t. Then I texted another friend asking her whereabouts. She was busy. This chain of reactions kept on going until I gave up and went into a random restaurant all by myself. Then it hit me. I did not even think about using Facebook, Twitter or any other social networks!  It was almost year 2014, and the current social networking solutions were not feasible for a face to face meet up!</p>

<!-- more -->


<p style="text-align:center">
<img src="/images/post/socialboredom.jpg">
</p>


<p>Most of the social networks are there to answer a question? It is just the way they exist.</p>

<ul>
<li>What are you up to? – Facebook.</li>
<li>What’s on your mind? – Twitter.</li>
<li>What picture do you want to share? – Instagram.</li>
<li>Where are you? – Foursquare.</li>
</ul>


<p>Obviously all the current social networks provide solutions for past time events of our lives. Present time at best. But none of them are actually designed to answer the question that can bring people together in real life.</p>

<p>Yes you can post a status update on Facebook, or tweet about it, or share your location and earn points, but none of these methods are in fact ideal to be used when you want to socialize in real life.
I have been talking with lots of young people especially between ages 16-24, and let me tell you, they are CRAVING for alternative solutions with regards to their socializing needs. One of them once told me “what is the point of using social networks if it does not help me get together with my friends in real life?” Another had told me that “social networks are only good for virtual socializing” which made me think about it even deeper. What is the purpose of social networks?
That is why we need alternative applications like Socialeyes, so that we remember that the actual socializing experience is still to be improved in the years ahead. It should not be about what I did last night, but rather should be about “what I want to do at the moment” and “what will I be doing in the future.”</p>

<p>Another mistake I see in today’s location based social networks is that they expect you to type down your intentions. Well hello! The users like to press, click, swipe, but they are not a huge fan of “typing” especially when it comes to announcing their social intentions. Typing “who is up for coffee?” on Facebook is perhaps not the best way to express your short term plans. You may not receive any likes, comments or messages causing the user to feel bad about him/herself. It is more of a “loser” feeling for the user when the post is unanswered. Besides the friends have to check their newsfeed very frequently so that they can see these open invitations. The time when a friend even notices that a friend was nearby and/or was up for an activity, would be later that day, probably seeing it posted couple of hours ago. Well how about using “push notifications”? But then again we come to the same problem that none of the social networks are designed that way.</p>

<p>Apps and the solutions they provide will always evolve and bring new ideas to the app world. That is why I believe new apps should be given a chance so that the big players out there know that they have to do better to serve their users. Do you also feel that there has to be a change in today’s social networking apps? We would love to hear your opinion! Drop us a note at <a href="&#x6d;&#97;&#105;&#x6c;&#x74;&#x6f;&#x3a;&#115;&#117;&#x70;&#x70;&#x6f;&#114;&#116;&#64;&#115;&#x6f;&#x63;&#x69;&#x61;&#x6c;&#x65;&#x79;&#x65;&#115;&#97;&#112;&#112;&#x2e;&#x63;&#x6f;&#109;">&#x73;&#x75;&#x70;&#112;&#x6f;&#x72;&#x74;&#x40;&#115;&#111;&#x63;&#105;&#97;&#x6c;&#101;&#121;&#101;&#x73;&#x61;&#x70;&#112;&#46;&#x63;&#x6f;&#109;</a> or tweet @socialeyesapp</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why Pay $19 bn to Whatsapp and Have the Facebook Messenger Split?]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/blog/2014/08/08/why-pay-9-bn-to-whatsapp-and-have-the-facebook-messenger-split/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-08T05:02:48-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/blog/2014/08/08/why-pay-9-bn-to-whatsapp-and-have-the-facebook-messenger-split</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Don’t really know who is in charge for the business strategies of Facebook but one thing I know for sure is that Facebook Messenger split decision was a wrong decision. And here is why.</p>

<!-- more -->




<p style="text-align:center">
<img src="/images/post/fbapp.jpg">
</p>


<p>Forcing Facebook users to go to another app is not a pleasant experience for the users. They were happy using Facebook chat as part of their Facebook experience. And when these people wanted to text a friend, they would simply switch to Whatsapp (over 500 million users) and do the texting over there. Same technology, almost the same interface and very similar experience.
With this aggressive and risky move, what Facebook is telling to its users is that, do not go to Whatsapp to text your friend and use the messenger instead. I do not know about you folks but I think $19 billion dollars is a LOT OF money. That is why we keep asking ourselves as Team Socialeyes, “why on earth pay $19 bn, and then try to destroy your own product?” In marketing there is a term for this. It is called cannibalization meaning that Facebook is hurting its own investment by another product that they own.</p>

<p>The correct way to approach this competition could have been like this: Do not spend $19 bn and then make the Facebook Messenger split decision. This Facebook Messenger split decision is a very aggressive and risky move and therefore it does not make sense to apply both strategies at the same time. Why acquire the hottest product on the market and then create competition against it in a way that will cause unhappiness among its current Facebook users. A marketing strategy professor once said, “The worst strategy is to have many strategies at the same time.” In other words, Facebook applies two different strategies at the same time and they do not go well together.</p>

<p>The recent research showed that the majority of young Facebook users are abandoning the brand for good due to its recent moves in the market. They are not happy with the way Facebook has become over the past few years. The product changed many times and most of the time they were not brilliant user interface changes such as timeline. Or any other change you can think of. Lots of ads, bad treatment to user, almost zero customer support, lots of changes in algorithms for fan pages…</p>

<p>Very soon, Facebook will start forcing their users to download and use Facebook Messenger. Let’s wait and see what the outcomes will be. Are you also against the split decision, or do you think Facebook is doing the right thing by Messenger? We would love to hear your opinion, mail us at <a href="&#x6d;&#x61;&#x69;&#x6c;&#116;&#x6f;&#58;&#x73;&#117;&#x70;&#112;&#x6f;&#114;&#116;&#x40;&#115;&#x6f;&#99;&#105;&#97;&#108;&#101;&#121;&#101;&#x73;&#x61;&#112;&#x70;&#46;&#x63;&#x6f;&#109;">&#115;&#117;&#x70;&#112;&#x6f;&#x72;&#116;&#64;&#115;&#111;&#x63;&#105;&#97;&#x6c;&#101;&#x79;&#x65;&#x73;&#x61;&#x70;&#x70;&#x2e;&#x63;&#x6f;&#x6d;</a> or tweet @socialeyesapp</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hello from Socialeyes]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/blog/2014/07/08/hello-socialeyes/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-08T10:19:12-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/blog/2014/07/08/hello-socialeyes</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We are very excited for the upcoming days. Because we are about to make our initial release to public. By Socialeyes, we are willing to help everyone to socialize easier. No, we are not
talking about a new way to share your videos, nor your articles, nor your pictures from last night. We are talking about getting together with your beloved ones face to face. We are talking
about unplanned spontaneous hangouts.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Because this is our first blog post, we wanted to introduce ourselves, what we do, what we think, why we do what we do, and who we are.
We want to make the world a better place. Absolutely noooot! An app cannot make the world a better place. An app can only make people’s lives easier and more entertaining. That is what we do. Make your social lives easier. A “good morning”, a warm smile, yielding in traffic can make the world a better place. Green Peace and Peace Corps are already working on project Earth. They are pretty good at it.
<img src="/images/post/IMG_3025.JPG"></p>

<p>We are 6 people. One business guy who thinks that he can always come up with crazy ideas, one designer who thinks that beautiful design is the difference between failure and success, and 4 developers who are pretty good at what they are doing. We love to watch Game of Thrones (at least most of us) Silicon Valley (because Aviato is the real thing) and go to movies from time to time. We all live a simple life. We work from home most of the time and get together a few times a week. We do this not because we don’t like each other but because we think this is more efficient and the technology gives us this chance.
<img src="/images/post/IMG_3763.JPG"></p>

<p>We blog because we have things to say. There are many right and many wrong things about the world we live in and we want our voice to be heard too. We want our blog posts to focus on people, social life and tech. If there is a new trend we will talk about it. If there is something wrong with a trend we will bring it out. If we think there is something funny about people, we will share it with you.
<img src="/images/post/IMG_5441.JPG"></p>

<p>We would love to hear from you. Your feedbacks, your thoughts, your compliments, criticisms, anything! So whenever you want to, please reach us at support[at]socialeyesapp.com</p>

<p><img src="/images/post/IMG_8993.JPG"></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
