<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Socialeyes Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-02-07T18:14:17-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Socialeyes]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Let life surprise you! Predictability is becoming obsolete]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/blog/2015/02/07/let-life-surprise-you-predictability-is-becoming-obsolete/"/>
    <updated>2015-02-07T18:06:13-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/blog/2015/02/07/let-life-surprise-you-predictability-is-becoming-obsolete</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This week was special for many people and hopefully  for you as well. Not because you got excited of news about “Tinder Plus”. <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2015/02/02/tinder-plus-the-paid-version-featuring-an-undo-button-and-more-arrives-in-u-s-next-month/">http://techcrunch.com/2015/02/02/tinder-plus-the-paid-version-featuring-an-undo-button-and-more-arrives-in-u-s-next-month/</a>. This other moment, when you thought &ldquo;Wow, I didn&rsquo;t expect that to happen. It should happen way more often!&rdquo;</p>

<p>There are more of this moments than we tend to realize. Sometimes it just needs a little reminder. <a href="http://lifehacker.com/carry-a-surprise-journal-to-find-areas-for-self-impro-1638467349">http://lifehacker.com/carry-a-surprise-journal-to-find-areas-for-self-impro-1638467349</a></p>

<!-- more -->


<p style="text-align:center">
<img src="http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/images/post/socializing-with-people.jpg" width="600" height="240">
</p>


<p>Somehow you found your way to this blog. Maybe on purpose or maybe by accident. No matter how, it seems like you are as passionate about people, socializing and technology as we are.</p>

<p>Technology has become a great tool for those, who love people. There are many new ways for those who are passionate about getting in touch with new spirits. Anyway it is hard to substitute the energy you feel when you get in touch with people <a href="http://www.entrepreneur.com/article/236752">http://www.entrepreneur.com/article/236752</a>.</p>

<p>Sometimes the way we are using technology is drifting away from the original purpose. Everyone knows the point when you start realizing that some of your routines shifted from supporting real life encounters to using technology for its own sake.</p>

<p>Instead of enjoying the thrill of possible rejection, we use technology to find a match before meeting.</p>

<p>Instead of planing a trip, we use technology to find the quickest route.</p>

<p>Instead of looking forward to meetings, we use technology to optimize our schedule.</p>

<p>The most beautiful moments of socializing don’t happen on purpose.</p>

<p>It’s this moment when you’ve been heavily procrastinating to call an old friend and just stumble into him at the small café you haven&rsquo;t been to for a year.</p>

<p>It’s this moment when you meet a business partner at a concert and discover that both of you fell in love with the same punk band twenty years ago.</p>

<p>It’s this moment when you start talking to a stranger in a hostel and end up spending a whole weekend together discovering a new city.</p>

<p>Those are the moments when you start realizing that it’s not always about optimizing your day. Often it&rsquo;s the spontaneous encounters that bring  more value to your life. (ted)</p>

<p>Now ask yourself two questions: &ldquo;Was there a moment this week, I hope to remember in the future? Did this moment happen exactly the way I pictured it last week?&rdquo;</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s time to put the spotlight on people again and let technology help you encounter more of those spontaneous moments. Reflect about this topic on your preferred channel with the hashtag #liveisspontan (no feeds yet, can be our thing) and get in touch with us to create more of this moments together.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Don’t Do These Mistakes on Your LinkedIn Profile]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/blog/2014/10/12/dont-do-these-mistakes-on-your-linkedin-profile/"/>
    <updated>2014-10-12T10:21:21-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/blog/2014/10/12/dont-do-these-mistakes-on-your-linkedin-profile</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Your job. One of the most important things in your life. Some of us spend more time on our jobs than for ourselves. That is why a good job can change your life for better.</p>

<p>We as team Socialeyes, started to look for candidates who will join our marketing team. And boy, we have seen some details that we have never paid attention to before. Here are some important details to look at on your LinkedIn profile that can turn a “no” to a “yes”.</p>

<!-- more -->




<p style="text-align:center">
<img src="http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/images/post/linkedin-hr.jpg">
</p>


<ul>
<li>Profile picture: If you do not have a profile picture, you will not be hired. That is for sure. Be careful with the picture you put up there. Remember this is LinkedIn, not Instagram or Facebook. People want to see your face, what you look like, if you seem like a nice person etc. A good smile is always a plus. It could give the message to the recruiter, “I would like to work with this guy”. Do not over-smile though.</li>
<li>Be reachable: How will the person contact you? With email? With phone? Fill in the contact part on your profile. Make sure you indicate an email address.</li>
<li>Self-Marketing: In this ad, we are looking for a Growth Hacker / Digital Marketing Manager. Some of the applicants are not even aware of the fact that their first project starts with marketing themselves to the recruiter. Please take another look at your profile when it is finished and ask this question to yourself “would I hire this person?”.</li>
<li>Be concise: Keep in mind that the average time a recruiter takes for an application is in seconds! Make sure you do not give too much detail, but just enough detail, so that the person would like to have an interview with you. Keep it to the point and avoid too long explanations in your past experiences.</li>
<li>Attach a resume: It is always handy to have a resume in hand. The recruiters can file them and look at it when the time comes.</li>
</ul>


<p>Cover letter, or in other approach, why you want this job really changes things. If you want this job, make the person know why this should be you, be different. If there are other details you look at please share with us, we’ll pay attention to those details as well (<a href="&#x6d;&#97;&#105;&#x6c;&#x74;&#111;&#x3a;&#x73;&#x75;&#x70;&#112;&#111;&#x72;&#x74;&#x40;&#115;&#111;&#99;&#105;&#97;&#108;&#x65;&#121;&#x65;&#x73;&#97;&#112;&#x70;&#x2e;&#99;&#x6f;&#109;">&#115;&#x75;&#x70;&#x70;&#111;&#114;&#116;&#x40;&#x73;&#x6f;&#99;&#x69;&#97;&#x6c;&#x65;&#x79;&#101;&#x73;&#x61;&#112;&#x70;&#46;&#x63;&#111;&#109;</a>).</p>

<p>And surely let us know if you want to be a part of our amazing team. <a href="http://www.socialeyesapp.com/jobs">http://www.socialeyesapp.com/jobs</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Updating App Designs for iPhone 6 and 6 Plus]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/blog/2014/09/18/updating-app-designs-for-iphone-6-and-6-plus/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-18T05:58:51-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/blog/2014/09/18/updating-app-designs-for-iphone-6-and-6-plus</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The fact that Apple is releasing not one, but two models of iPhone surprised me despite all the rumors going around. As an iOS Developer, my first impulse was a longing for the days where all you had to deal with was a 320x480 screen and place every view and not give it a second thought.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Now that the dust has somewhat settled, supporting three screens with different widths doesn’t seem much harder than supporting two. Apple had already provided the tools to handle this kind of scenario and tools like <a href="http://www.paintcodeapp.com/">PaintCode</a> or <a href="https://github.com/mindbrix/UIImage-PDF">UIImage-PDF</a>  make it easy to handle scalable assets.</p>

<p>Figuring out good practices for updating app designs seems a bit more challenging. The fact that the new iPhones have the same screen ratio as iPhone 5 makes it easy to simply scale up every component to fit screen; indeed unupdated apps are scaled up for iPhone 6 and 6+. But this is just to ensure compatibility.</p>

<p>When you take a look at the iPhone 6 or 6+ screen, you will note that the heights of UI Elements like navigation bars and buttons have stayed the same. The screen is utilized to convey more elements and information, rather than bigger instances of the UI elements.</p>

<p>There are cases however when it is preferable to preserve the ratio of an UI element. Take a look at our feed screen in Socialeyes as seen in iPhone 5:</p>

<p style="text-align:center">
<img src="http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/images/post/iPhone6_1.png" title="right" >
</p>


<p>And here is the same screen, with only minor adjustments to ensure the cell is centered:</p>

<p>can<p style="text-align:center">
<img src="http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/images/post/iPhone6_2.png" title="right" >
</p></p>

<p>Clearly this not what we looking for. The left and right margins feel very unnecessary.</p>

<p>Let’s try preserving the margins:</p>

<p style="text-align:center">
<img src="http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/images/post/iPhone6_3.png" title="right" >
</p>


<p>This feels a bit better but proportionality feels a bit off. I don’t think our designer will be happy with this.</p>

<p>After increasing the height of the colored areas we reserve for activities and increasing the font size a bit, this is the result:</p>

<p style="text-align:center">
<img src="http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/images/post/iPhone6_4.png" title="right" >
</p>


<p>This looks much better. There are a lot of room for improvement but for now this will do.</p>

<p>The best practices and standards for app design is in flux and I find this very exciting. Our rule of thumb for now is to fix what seems off. Hopefully we will figure out ways to make good use of the new screen sizes rather than just ensuring that things look okay.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cannot Concentrate on Anything!]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/blog/2014/09/02/cannot-concentrate-on-anything/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-02T04:29:43-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/blog/2014/09/02/cannot-concentrate-on-anything</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Sounds familiar? Well this is the case for most of us. If you have a job that requires you to spend hours in front of your computer, this is most likely to be the case for you too. You will start your day, determined to finish most of your tasks. In a couple of hours or so, you will realize that your to-do list is still piling up! But how did this happen? You spent hours in front of your computer.</p>

<!-- more -->




<p style="text-align:center">
<img src="http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/images/post/concentration-kid.jpg" title="right" >
</p>


<p>This is probably the disease of our generation. Call it ADD (Attention Deficit Disorder) or call it whatever you want to call. In today’s digital social media age, the chances you will be distracted while doing anything is significantly high. This is probably why most of the creative workers prefer working at night rather than daylight. You start your day with a clean desktop and sometime in the afternoon you find yourself literally lost among bunch of opened up browsers, apps, paperwork etc.</p>

<p>Generation Y by nature gets bored easily. Adding this to the list makes it even worse for anyone of us to concentrate on our tasks and get it done although we spend hours. If you want to keep concentrated, the main trick is to take control of your tiny distractions and only delay them for your next time out. So how to avoid being distracted and get jobs done fast? Here are a couple of tricks that can help you.</p>

<h2>3 Tabs or 3 Windows Rule</h2>

<p>Never ever have more than 3 tabs open in your Internet browser. Internet surfing can be tricky after sometime. Opening up a new window or tab can lead you to a jungle of new content at the end of which you will not even remember why you opened the other tabs at the first place.</p>

<h2>Phone Notification Rule</h2>

<p>Do not let your phone take control of you. You take control of your phone. A push notification can wait for your next pause. If you let each notification get to you then you will end up losing focus every time.</p>

<h2>Have your holy 30 mins break every day</h2>

<p>No matter how busy your day is, remember to spend half an hour to yourself every day. Whether this can be reading a book, or watching your favorite TV show, simply close your doors to the rest of the world, avoid talking to anyone, turn off your phone, and do whatever that is you like on your spare times. You can think of these concentration cycles as a therapy to educate your brain to work in a more focused way.</p>

<h2>Always log out after your Social Media session</h2>

<p>God knows how many times we opened up Facebook for looking at a specific thing and ended up being lost. Your Facebook breaks are fun and necessary in a way. But it is critical to log out at the end of each session so that you do not let Facebook take control of you, but rather you take control of Facebook.</p>

<h2>Keep your TV off</h2>

<p>This is no brainer, if there are other random voices playing in the background, the chances you will finish your job is less. Shut it off.</p>

<h2>Listen to Music</h2>

<p>Listening to your favorite tunes can be a good choice to keep yourself focused. Be careful with 3 details though. The music should not be very loud, you should not be changing tracks each time the music stops and you should not be disturbing the people around you.</p>

<p>Now that you have finished reading this article, you can close this distraction tab and get back to work. C’mon chop chop!
What are your thoughts on concentration problems, write to us: support [at] socialeyespp dot com
Or tweet us: @socialeyesapp #eyesapp</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How do we socialize?]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/blog/2014/08/26/how-do-we-socialize/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-26T05:30:55-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/blog/2014/08/26/how-do-we-socialize</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Socializing is in our nature. While the very basics of how we interact such as <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Handshake">handshaking</a> are both widespread and ages old, the specifics has always been in flux. Social occasions that our interactions revolve around, change across different ages and cultures.</p>

<!-- more -->




<p style="text-align:center">
<img src="http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/images/post/handshake.jpg" title="right" >
</p>


<p>Perhaps the more radical changes are to do with the medium of our social interactions. The advent of the world wide web and mobile devices has given us tools that allow us to communicate in ways we could only imagine. The trend has been to increase the amount of people we can interact with.</p>

<p>Socialeyes is our take on how people could interact today. Our focus is to help our users socialize with their friends in real life rather than a horde of acquaintances online.
We want our users to shake hands.</p>

<p>Socialeyes helps people share what they are in the mood for, so that they could meet on the fly.</p>

<p>We have gathered some information directly from our database to see how do people use Socialeyes to meet up;</p>

<h2>Most social day of week</h2>

<p>Of course it&rsquo;s Saturday! Are we surprised? No! Saturday and Sunday are given as weekend in all working societies.
As a result %53 of the social gathering requests made in weekends. Wednesday is the most social working day in a week.
I guess we get a little bit overwhelmed with work and school in the middle of the week, we would like to meet with our beloved ones.</p>

<h2>Most social hours of the day</h2>

<p>Mostly we love to get together when the sun is at the top. %26 of the meeting requests are posted between 11:00AM to 01:00PM.
When we have a lunch break at the office or a little bit time between the classes in the school all we can think of is meeting with friends.
The socializing requests continue with lowering percentages until 09:00PM.</p>

<h2>Most popular social activities</h2>

<p>For certain, we most love to grab a coffee, chilling with friends  with a little bit chit chat.
Approximately, %38 of the socializing requests are drinking coffee, chatting and chilling with friends.
We can clearly see listening to music is one of the indispensable activities of all the time with %13.5 ratio. (I was listening to <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7jr1uk2SvbY">http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7jr1uk2SvbY</a> while I am writing this blog post.)</p>

<h2>Most social areas of the world</h2>

<p>Socialeyes is used in United States by far the most with nearly %60 usage. The Middle East and Asia comes the second. Europe, Africa and South America are in the bottom of the list with least usage,
whether these continents need no socializing tool or no social at all. Come on! give Socialeyes a shot, we aim to make you meet with your friends easily.</p>

<p>Here we have prepared an infographic with many more details than described above. Please check it out for more details!</p>

<script id="infogram_0_how-do-we-socialize" src="//e.infogr.am/js/embed.js" type="text/javascript"></script>


<div style="width:100%;border-top:1px solid #acacac;padding-top:3px;font-family:Arial;font-size:10px;text-align:center;"><a target="_blank" href="//infogr.am/how-do-we-socialize" style="color:#acacac;text-decoration:none;">How do we Socıalıze</a> | <a style="color:#acacac;text-decoration:none;" href="//infogr.am" target="_blank">Create Infographics</a></div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hey Facebook! This is What We Want]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/blog/2014/08/25/hey-facebook-this-is-what-we-want/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-25T11:14:43-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/blog/2014/08/25/hey-facebook-this-is-what-we-want</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There are times when being on Facebook is a painful experience. We spend about 30 mins daily on average on Facebook. I am pretty sure there have been times when you got tired of browsing only because of some small details that should have been different to make your experience a better one. I feel that if Facebook made some minor changes in its App/Web Page, it would be a beter experience for the user.</p>

<p style="text-align:center">
<img src="http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/images/post/facebook.jpg">
</p>




<!-- more -->


<p>Here are some of the main ones:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Just show me the most recent posts</p></li>
<li><p>When a friend makes a comment about a post, this should not bring the post to the top of the feed again. Just bring me the most recent ones. I am not interested in the same post that I saw 3 hours ago. This is only okay if someone has mentioned me.</p></li>
<li><p>I do not care if someone has liked another post. Seeing other people liked someone else’s post prevents me from liking more stuff on Facebook. If you are an Instagram and Facebook user at the same time, you can see the clearest proof of this. Simply post the same photo to both of your accounts simultaneously. Although you have more friends on Facebook the likes you will receive on Instagram will be more than Facebook. I guarantee.</p></li>
<li><p>You should do a better job with notifications. The goal is to keep connected. Let me know when someone has commented on my post or liked my things etc.</p></li>
<li><p>For God’s sake put an end to this Facebook Messenger bu&hellip;hit. If I want to use a different app to text to my friends I have Whatsapp! (Remember the time you paid $19,000,000,000?) Stop forcing me to leave the app.</p></li>
<li><p>Facebook is not good enough for my face-to-face socializing needs. Try to come up with better product/app so that people do not only socialize virtually but also get out and meet in real life. Pay attention to startups like Socialeyes that concentrate on these sorts of problems. See them as a potential target for acquiring and making a better product.</p></li>
<li><p>Make your privacy settings easier. It is really painful to figure out each one of them and change them.</p></li>
<li><p>I may not want to be tagged in a photo. Get my permission first. Although you offer this feature, when a friend tags me, it appears on everyone&rsquo;s news feed anyway. Come up with a better privacy feature to solve this problem.</p></li>
</ul>


<p>Enough criticism. Special thanks to Mark Zuckerberg for the whole ALS ice bucket thing. If it wasn’t for him, this movement may not have reached to so many people around the world. Good job Mark!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What is the ALS Ice Bucket Challenge?]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/blog/2014/08/18/what-is-the-als-ice-bucket-challenge/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-18T12:05:56-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/blog/2014/08/18/what-is-the-als-ice-bucket-challenge</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you have not seen this viral and social game already, you will certainly see one in the near future. A friend of yours appears in a video saying that he/she was nominated for ALS by this and that person, and nominates a couple of other people to do the same. And they are given 24 hours to complete the task. Then what? A bucket of iced water is being poured down over the head. It is funny, it is viral and it also benefits society. It is genius!</p>

<h2>WHY ALS?</h2>

<p>ALS is a disease that gradually damages nerve cells that control muscles. In other words, it makes people lose control over their muscles, meaning they slowly lose the ability to walk, speak, eat and breath. People with ALS have a life expectancy of 2 to 5 years. The serious thing here is that there’s no treatment and the only approved drug buys just a little bit more time. The whole purpose of this challenge is to raise awareness (which is right on!) and raise money for ALS. As of last week, the ALS association received $4 million of charity within the past month. Obviously things got a bit wilder once Facebook’s Mark Zuckerberg got nominated to do the ALS Ice Bucket Challenge. The amount of charity collected for the week after Mark’s nomination video is not revealed yet but obviously it created a huge traction for the ALS Ice Bucket Challenge.</p>

<h2>WHY ICE BUCKET?</h2>

<p>It makes sense. It is summer time (at least for most of the people), it is a bit challenging and anyone use a bit refreshment on these hot summer days. Besides it is funny to see people dumping iced water over their heads.</p>

<h2>WHAT IS THE CHALLENGE?</h2>

<p>Either dump the bucket of iced water over the head, or donate $100 to ALS association.</p>

<h2>WHO HAS DONE IT?</h2>

<p>There are lots of celebrities who have been challenged and have accepted. Among the famous people here are our favorite ALS Ice Bucket Challenge videos:</p>

<h3>Mark Zuckerberg</h3>

<div class="embed-video-container"><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/6TTpXKFBkjk" width="854" height="480" allowfullscreen></iframe></div>


<h3>Bill Gates</h3>

<div class="embed-video-container"><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/XS6ysDFTbLU" width="854" height="480" allowfullscreen></iframe></div>


<h3>Jimmy Fallon with Rob Riggle, Horatio Sanz, Steve Higgins, The Roots</h3>

<div class="embed-video-container"><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/b_kdke345NQ" width="854" height="480" allowfullscreen></iframe></div>


<h3>Justin Timberlake</h3>

<div class="embed-video-container"><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/-4smHMO1Crg" width="854" height="480" allowfullscreen></iframe></div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Are People Really Getting Tired of Social Networks?]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/blog/2014/08/11/are-people-really-getting-tired-of-social-networks/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-11T06:08:10-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/blog/2014/08/11/are-people-really-getting-tired-of-social-networks</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A year ago I was out of a meeting and starting walking in a very busy district in the city. It was about lunch time and I was starving. I wanted to grab a bite but did not want to do it alone. So I called a friend of mine hoping he would be somewhere nearby. He wasn’t. Then I texted another friend asking her whereabouts. She was busy. This chain of reactions kept on going until I gave up and went into a random restaurant all by myself. Then it hit me. I did not even think about using Facebook, Twitter or any other social networks!  It was almost year 2014, and the current social networking solutions were not feasible for a face to face meet up!</p>

<!-- more -->


<p style="text-align:center">
<img src="http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/images/post/socialboredom.jpg">
</p>


<p>Most of the social networks are there to answer a question? It is just the way they exist.</p>

<ul>
<li>What are you up to? – Facebook.</li>
<li>What’s on your mind? – Twitter.</li>
<li>What picture do you want to share? – Instagram.</li>
<li>Where are you? – Foursquare.</li>
</ul>


<p>Obviously all the current social networks provide solutions for past time events of our lives. Present time at best. But none of them are actually designed to answer the question that can bring people together in real life.</p>

<p>Yes you can post a status update on Facebook, or tweet about it, or share your location and earn points, but none of these methods are in fact ideal to be used when you want to socialize in real life.
I have been talking with lots of young people especially between ages 16-24, and let me tell you, they are CRAVING for alternative solutions with regards to their socializing needs. One of them once told me “what is the point of using social networks if it does not help me get together with my friends in real life?” Another had told me that “social networks are only good for virtual socializing” which made me think about it even deeper. What is the purpose of social networks?
That is why we need alternative applications like Socialeyes, so that we remember that the actual socializing experience is still to be improved in the years ahead. It should not be about what I did last night, but rather should be about “what I want to do at the moment” and “what will I be doing in the future.”</p>

<p>Another mistake I see in today’s location based social networks is that they expect you to type down your intentions. Well hello! The users like to press, click, swipe, but they are not a huge fan of “typing” especially when it comes to announcing their social intentions. Typing “who is up for coffee?” on Facebook is perhaps not the best way to express your short term plans. You may not receive any likes, comments or messages causing the user to feel bad about him/herself. It is more of a “loser” feeling for the user when the post is unanswered. Besides the friends have to check their newsfeed very frequently so that they can see these open invitations. The time when a friend even notices that a friend was nearby and/or was up for an activity, would be later that day, probably seeing it posted couple of hours ago. Well how about using “push notifications”? But then again we come to the same problem that none of the social networks are designed that way.</p>

<p>Apps and the solutions they provide will always evolve and bring new ideas to the app world. That is why I believe new apps should be given a chance so that the big players out there know that they have to do better to serve their users. Do you also feel that there has to be a change in today’s social networking apps? We would love to hear your opinion! Drop us a note at <a href="&#x6d;&#x61;&#x69;&#x6c;&#x74;&#x6f;&#x3a;&#115;&#117;&#112;&#112;&#111;&#114;&#116;&#x40;&#x73;&#x6f;&#99;&#105;&#97;&#x6c;&#101;&#121;&#101;&#115;&#97;&#x70;&#112;&#46;&#99;&#x6f;&#109;">&#x73;&#117;&#x70;&#112;&#x6f;&#114;&#116;&#64;&#x73;&#111;&#99;&#x69;&#x61;&#108;&#101;&#121;&#101;&#115;&#x61;&#112;&#112;&#x2e;&#99;&#111;&#x6d;</a> or tweet @socialeyesapp</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why Pay $19 bn to Whatsapp and Have the Facebook Messenger Split?]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/blog/2014/08/08/why-pay-9-bn-to-whatsapp-and-have-the-facebook-messenger-split/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-08T05:02:48-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/blog/2014/08/08/why-pay-9-bn-to-whatsapp-and-have-the-facebook-messenger-split</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Don’t really know who is in charge for the business strategies of Facebook but one thing I know for sure is that Facebook Messenger split decision was a wrong decision. And here is why.</p>

<!-- more -->




<p style="text-align:center">
<img src="http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/images/post/fbapp.jpg">
</p>


<p>Forcing Facebook users to go to another app is not a pleasant experience for the users. They were happy using Facebook chat as part of their Facebook experience. And when these people wanted to text a friend, they would simply switch to Whatsapp (over 500 million users) and do the texting over there. Same technology, almost the same interface and very similar experience.
With this aggressive and risky move, what Facebook is telling to its users is that, do not go to Whatsapp to text your friend and use the messenger instead. I do not know about you folks but I think $19 billion dollars is a LOT OF money. That is why we keep asking ourselves as Team Socialeyes, “why on earth pay $19 bn, and then try to destroy your own product?” In marketing there is a term for this. It is called cannibalization meaning that Facebook is hurting its own investment by another product that they own.</p>

<p>The correct way to approach this competition could have been like this: Do not spend $19 bn and then make the Facebook Messenger split decision. This Facebook Messenger split decision is a very aggressive and risky move and therefore it does not make sense to apply both strategies at the same time. Why acquire the hottest product on the market and then create competition against it in a way that will cause unhappiness among its current Facebook users. A marketing strategy professor once said, “The worst strategy is to have many strategies at the same time.” In other words, Facebook applies two different strategies at the same time and they do not go well together.</p>

<p>The recent research showed that the majority of young Facebook users are abandoning the brand for good due to its recent moves in the market. They are not happy with the way Facebook has become over the past few years. The product changed many times and most of the time they were not brilliant user interface changes such as timeline. Or any other change you can think of. Lots of ads, bad treatment to user, almost zero customer support, lots of changes in algorithms for fan pages…</p>

<p>Very soon, Facebook will start forcing their users to download and use Facebook Messenger. Let’s wait and see what the outcomes will be. Are you also against the split decision, or do you think Facebook is doing the right thing by Messenger? We would love to hear your opinion, mail us at <a href="&#x6d;&#97;&#x69;&#x6c;&#x74;&#x6f;&#x3a;&#115;&#x75;&#x70;&#x70;&#111;&#x72;&#x74;&#x40;&#115;&#x6f;&#x63;&#105;&#97;&#108;&#x65;&#121;&#101;&#115;&#97;&#112;&#x70;&#x2e;&#x63;&#111;&#109;">&#x73;&#117;&#112;&#112;&#x6f;&#x72;&#x74;&#x40;&#x73;&#111;&#x63;&#105;&#x61;&#108;&#101;&#x79;&#x65;&#115;&#x61;&#x70;&#112;&#46;&#99;&#111;&#109;</a> or tweet @socialeyesapp</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Feedback: Road to success]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/blog/2014/08/05/feedback-road-to-success/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-05T14:48:58-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/blog/2014/08/05/feedback-road-to-success</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>User feedback is key to success. While developing a product, startup&rsquo;s sources are limited. Some designers, couple of engineers, a product owner and a limited amount of beta users are creating, reviewing and testing the product with limited resources. People work hard for months maybe years to create a usable, viable product. These people are using and seeing that product tons of times a day. At that point people in the team become blind about their product day by day. The way the product looks, they way the product works are becoming ordinary and standard for these people. As time passes by the team loses their creativity and development power on the product. People with new perspective, people with a neutral point of view are needed for the product to move on.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>At that point new users and user feedback becomes vital! This is an obligatory process in the lifecycle of a mature, useful product. Objective feedback is indispensable for your product development.
Feedback helps;
&ndash; to evolve
&ndash; to track down weak spots
&ndash; to grow it&rsquo;s audience
&ndash; to give opinions about your user base
&ndash; to change your point of view
&ndash; to implement better ideas
&ndash; to identify users needs</p>

<p style="text-align:center">
<img src="http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/images/post/feedback.jpg">
</p>


<h1>What should be done to gain your audience&rsquo;s feedback?</h1>

<h2>Always include a feedback form in your product</h2>

<p>Place an easy, user friendly, reachable feedback form in your product or guide your users to email or tweet their feedbacks.</p>

<br />


<h2>Ask people what they think about your product</h2>

<p>Ask for feedback and their opinions as many people as you can. Try to observe people&rsquo;s behaviours while they are using your product.</p>

<br />


<h2>Always respond to users&#8217; feedbacks, be positive</h2>

<p>If possible respond every feedback with an dequate answer, be positive and constructive.</p>

<br />


<h2>Include technical details in your feedback information</h2>

<p>For inhouse usage; try to gather user&rsquo;s device information, OS information, implement a backlog for your product and check user&rsquo;s behaviours.</p>

<br />


<h2>Aggregate feedbacks by their type</h2>

<p>Aggregate feedbacks by common types and inspect them carefully. Observe feedback groups by time, they will tell you if there are common problems/common needs at certain points of your product.</p>

<br />


<p>There are lessons to be learned from feedbacks, try to gain as much feedback as you can. Analytics and statistics give some ideas but there may be still foggy areas as Danish football coach
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ebbe_Skovdahl">Ebbe Skovdahl</a> stated:</p>

<blockquote><p>Statistics are like mini-skirts, shows a lot of things but does not show what is essential.</p></blockquote>

<p>Feedback is a real, objective review of your product coming from a real human being which makes it invaluable.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[5 Simple tricks to increase battery life of your phone]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/blog/2014/08/03/5-simple-tricks-to-increase-battery-life-of-your-phone/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-03T09:14:36-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/blog/2014/08/03/5-simple-tricks-to-increase-battery-life-of-your-phone</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It is summer time. We spend our days on the beach getting sun tan, enjoying our Mojitos and swimming. During this summer relaxation, we take out our phones to take a selfie or text to our friends and we see the inevitable result on the top bar in our screens. The battery is running low! We all enjoy our apps and they will surely use some portion of our batteries. Looking for a charger could be painful on the beach. We all feel the need to play a game, take a look at our friends on Facebook, or simply listen to music while we enjoy ourselves on the beach. So how to tackle the battery problem? Here are a couple of simple tricks you can do to avoid the battery problems.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h3>1. Limit Location Related System Services:</h3>

<p>There are several location related system services that you might find unnecessary. You can finding these options in &ldquo;Settings > Privacy > Location Services > System Services&rdquo;. Be sure not to disable useful services such as &ldquo;Find my iPhone&rdquo;.</p>

<p style="text-align:center">
<img src="http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/images/post/system_services.png" width="200" height="80">
</p>


<h3>2. Limit Background App Refresh:</h3>

<p>You can limit how your apps update their data while in the background. Tap through &ldquo;Settings > General > Background App Refresh&rdquo;. You can also disable &ldquo;Background App Refresh&rdquo; altogether but it can be more convenient to allow frequently used applications to refresh in the background.</p>

<p style="text-align:center">
<img src="http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/images/post/background_refresh.png">
</p>


<h3>3. Turn your brightness lower:</h3>

<p> Go to “Brightness” section and turn your screen brightness to a lower level at which you can still see your screen but consume less energy. On sunny days this could be difficult given the fact that it will already be a bit more challenging to see what is going on your screen while the sun is shining.</p>

<p style="text-align:center">
<img src="http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/images/post/iphone-ios7-control-center.jpg">
</p>


<h3>4. Turn off Parallax Effect:</h3>

<p>As pretty as the parallax effect is, you might want to trade it for more battery life. You can disable this option in &ldquo;Settings > General > Accessibility > Reduce Motion&rdquo;.</p>

<p style="text-align:center">
<img src="http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/images/post/reduce_motion.png">
</p>


<h3>5. Limit Spotlight Search:</h3>

<p>Depending on how often you use spotlight search, it can be good idea to disable indexing data you are not interested in. Just go to &ldquo;Settings > General > Spotlight Search&rdquo; and disable the items that .you don&rsquo;t want to include in search results.</p>

<p style="text-align:center">
<img src="http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/images/post/spotlight_search.png">
</p>


<p>We hope that someday in the near future the phone companies will be able to come up with solutions to battery problems. After all we are living in an era where our apps are indispensable part of our lives and we feel like we lack part of our bodies when our phone battery is dead.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Summit Dublin]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/blog/2014/07/23/the-summit-dublin/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-23T11:16:40-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/blog/2014/07/23/the-summit-dublin</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As tech world grows with mobile and web products, the gatherings become more and more important everyday. Events, summits, workshops and meetings are the perfect place to track down new development in the business.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p><img class="right" src="http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/images/post/thesummit.jpg" width="350" height="350"></p>

<p>One of the biggest events in the world is <a href="http://www.summitdublin.com">“The Summit”</a>. In 4th- 6th November 2014 Dublin will host The Summit. As Wall Street Journal stated “The giants of the web assemble in Dublin”, many startups like Socialeyes and big players in the market will be in Dublin to create a huge buzz in the tech ecosystem.</p>

<p>Socialeyes is happy to be taking place in The Summit. We will try to explain what Socialeyes is doing, how Socialeyes integrates in your social life, makes it easier to meet your friends nearby by sharing your mood. The Summit Dublin will be a nice showcase for Socialeyes and we are so excited to be there.</p>

<p>If everything goes as planned we will be exhibiting Android version of Socialeyes and new UEX enhancements for iOS devices in The Summit Dublin – 2014.</p>

<p>Come visit us in Dublin, we will be happy to discuss anything about mobile and tech.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[World Cup Champions 2014]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/blog/2014/07/13/world-cup-champions-2014/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-13T20:09:45-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/blog/2014/07/13/world-cup-champions-2014</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It’s been one of the most entertaining World Cup tournaments in history. In the final we had two great sides. Germany against Argentina. Argentina did very good defensive work throughout the World Cup 2014. They came all the way to the final in this tournament hosted by their arch rivals. Winning the title could mean a lot more than just a championship for the Argentinians. Germans put out an excellent team performance in World Cup 2014 and deserved the Cup all the way.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p><img src="http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/images/post/germany2014.jpg"></p>

<p>Although there was much challenge and competition in the final, it would not be a fair assessment to say that the final game was a thrilling one. It ended in extra time by the spectacular half volley of Mario Gotze.</p>

<p>Neuer, the German goalkeeper was awarded the Golden Glove for his outstanding performance in World Cup 2014. Lionel Messi was awarded the Golden Ball. Let’s confess it, we all love Lionel Messi so much that even though his performances were behind some of the other names in the tournament like any German player, or Argentinian Garay, or Colombian James Rodriguez, we give him the award.</p>

<p>Let us not forget that despite the fact that Brazilian fans are pretty much disheartened by their performance in World Cup 2014, they hosted an amazing tournament. Let us also not forget that they finished in top 4. One of the highlights of the tournament will surely be their historical defeat by Germans with a unforgettable score of 7-1. For some, this score put the actual final in its shade.</p>

<p>We have had Portugal with Cristiano Ronaldo, Argentina with Lionel Messi, Netherlands with Arjen Robben, Brazil with Neymar… But the fact remains the same. Football, as we know it, is a team sport and Germany showed this to any football fan around the world. Let us all celebrate the winners and not forget that a world with sports is way more fun and exciting. Cheers All!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A World Cup Final Before The Actual World Cup Final]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/blog/2014/07/10/a-world-cup-final-before-the-actual-world-cup-final/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-10T03:24:57-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/blog/2014/07/10/a-world-cup-final-before-the-actual-world-cup-final</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It&rsquo;s almost the World Cup Final day. Yet the people talk about only one game. The epic defeat of Brazil by Germany. Surely millions of sports fans had not been expecting the 6 goal difference football show the other day. And it literally broke the hearts of the millions of Brazilian sports fans who were quite eager to see the final of the World Cup which was hosted by the Brazilians themselves. Here is a funny video that summarizes the whole semifinal defeat in ten seconds.</p>

<!-- more -->


<div class="embed-video-container"><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/gIUDNtb6qY0" width="854" height="480" allowfullscreen></iframe></div>


<p>We, the Socialeyes Team loved this video! The soundtrack playing the famous &ldquo;Brazil&rdquo; song, which is interrupted with a gigantic beer glass that has German flag on it that crushes the cocktail glass that represents Brazil.</p>

<p>Obviously this game has already put the actual final in its shade. Now that we have Argentina matched up with Germany in the World Cup Final, fans will be expecting another goal show from the German Panzers. On the other hand, the host fans, will watch this World Cup Final with fear, hoping that their fierce rivals Argentina does not end up lifting up the World Cup. From another point of view, surely the streets of Buenos Aires will watch a very exciting World Cup Final hoping that they end up becoming the champions of the World Cup in Brazil.</p>

<p>So the question here is: will we see another video of Argentinian Wine Glass smashed by the Gigantic German Glass, or will Lionel Messi&rsquo;s Argentina bring the title home by making their fans proud on this special World Cup Final.</p>

<p>Now we know that many fans worldwide are expecting to see their idol, Lionel Messi to lift the World Cup, making him a true football legend and take his place in history. On the other hand, we have a very strong and on form German team that displays excellence in team play.</p>

<p>All we know that on Sunday night, millions of people all across the globe will watch the World Cup Final without the blink of an eye. And us, as the Socialeyes Team will light up our barbeque, have our favorite beers in our hands and enjoy this most entertaining sports event with our beloved fans.
You think the Germans will win? Or is it going to be the night for Argentinian Tango.</p>

<p>Send us what you think support[at]socialeyesapp.com</p>

<p>Or simply tweet us @socialeyesapp</p>

<p>Or socialize with us on Facebook <a href="https://www.facebook.com/pages/Socialeyes/360111724123590">https://www.facebook.com/pages/Socialeyes/360111724123590</a></p>

<p>Goallll!!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hello from Socialeyes]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/blog/2014/07/08/hello-socialeyes/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-08T10:19:12-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/blog/2014/07/08/hello-socialeyes</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We are very excited for the upcoming days. Because we are about to make our initial release to public. By Socialeyes, we are willing to help everyone to socialize easier. No, we are not
talking about a new way to share your videos, nor your articles, nor your pictures from last night. We are talking about getting together with your beloved ones face to face. We are talking
about unplanned spontaneous hangouts.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Because this is our first blog post, we wanted to introduce ourselves, what we do, what we think, why we do what we do, and who we are.
We want to make the world a better place. Absolutely noooot! An app cannot make the world a better place. An app can only make people’s lives easier and more entertaining. That is what we do. Make your social lives easier. A “good morning”, a warm smile, yielding in traffic can make the world a better place. Green Peace and Peace Corps are already working on project Earth. They are pretty good at it.
<img src="http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/images/post/IMG_3025.JPG"></p>

<p>We are 6 people. One business guy who thinks that he can always come up with crazy ideas, one designer who thinks that beautiful design is the difference between failure and success, and 4 developers who are pretty good at what they are doing. We love to watch Game of Thrones (at least most of us) Silicon Valley (because Aviato is the real thing) and go to movies from time to time. We all live a simple life. We work from home most of the time and get together a few times a week. We do this not because we don’t like each other but because we think this is more efficient and the technology gives us this chance.
<img src="http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/images/post/IMG_3763.JPG"></p>

<p>We blog because we have things to say. There are many right and many wrong things about the world we live in and we want our voice to be heard too. We want our blog posts to focus on people, social life and tech. If there is a new trend we will talk about it. If there is something wrong with a trend we will bring it out. If we think there is something funny about people, we will share it with you.
<img src="http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/images/post/IMG_5441.JPG"></p>

<p>We would love to hear from you. Your feedbacks, your thoughts, your compliments, criticisms, anything! So whenever you want to, please reach us at support[at]socialeyesapp.com</p>

<p><img src="http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/images/post/IMG_8993.JPG"></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
