<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: liveisspontan | Socialeyes Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/blog/categories/liveisspontan/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-03-17T20:55:58-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Socialeyes]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Socialeyes Launched!]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/blog/2015/03/03/new-socialeyes-launched/"/>
    <updated>2015-03-03T08:00:03-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/blog/2015/03/03/new-socialeyes-launched</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>It all started with a simple problem</h2>




<p style="text-align:center">
<img src="/images/post/featureGraphic.png" title="center" >
</p>


<p>It was about three year ago it hit me. I wanted to grab a cup of coffee with a friend and I thought none of the traditional ways of communication was actually helping me to do this.</p>

<p>Texting or calling friends: Yes it is probably the best way to do this. But think about it. Can you do this every time you want to do something? What if your friends will have to say no most of the time because they are either busy or somewhere far away at the moment. On the other hand wouldn’t it sometimes be better to socialize with other circle of friends?</p>

<p>Facebook, Twitter: It might be hours later by the time my friends see that I was up for coffee 4 hours ago. Too late, no good. Besides let’s face it. It is not really cool to post something like “who’s up for coffee?” on your wall. And imagine doing this every time.</p>

<p>So we designed Socialeyes. We believed that asking friends to join us should be as simple as 1,2,3. We also thought life itself is a social game, so why don’t we design it in a way that it will be fun and cool at the same time.</p>

<p>And now ladies and gentlemen. We are proud to present you the months of hardwork, and dedication.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>What changed: The first thing you will notice is that the design has undergone a complete change. Colors, UI, UX, etc. Now there is only button at the bottom of the screen making it way easier for our first time users to post something. We have also gotten rid of some of the parts that can help the design become more simple. We gathered all the actions on the left menu. Here you will have access to your own profile, searchbox, friends list &amp; invitations, messages, and info section. On the right hand side of your main screen you will see notifications, well they haven’t much changed.</p>

<p>There have been also some changes to the concept. Now Socialeyes is a game! The more social you are, the more points you will earn. Every action, every interaction you do in the app earns you social score. This way you get to see how your social life has been. It shows your social identity, the things you like to do the most, the kind of person you are…</p>

<p>There is a leaderboard added to the left menu. Here you get to see which friends have been active, which have not. It adds to the fun dimension of the app.</p>

<p>When your friends are nearby you get notified as long as your “nearby” switch is “on”.</p>

<p>There has also been an addition to the “moods”. Now there are 12 moods and soon lot more are expected. Just so you know, our first users will have much more privileges, including the new moods.</p>

<p>Even if we can help you get one more glass of wine, one more quick lunch, one more cup of coffee with a friend, we will know our mission has been accomplished. We are hoping that you will enjoy Socialeyes just as much as we do.</p>

<p>Any thoughts? Comments? Feedback? Please share with us @socialeyesapp or email: <a href="&#x6d;&#97;&#x69;&#108;&#x74;&#x6f;&#x3a;&#x6a;&#111;&#104;&#110;&#x40;&#x73;&#111;&#x63;&#105;&#97;&#108;&#x65;&#121;&#x65;&#115;&#x61;&#112;&#112;&#x2e;&#x63;&#111;&#109;">&#106;&#x6f;&#x68;&#110;&#64;&#x73;&#111;&#x63;&#105;&#x61;&#x6c;&#x65;&#121;&#101;&#115;&#97;&#x70;&#112;&#46;&#99;&#x6f;&#109;</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Let life surprise you! Predictability is becoming obsolete]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/blog/2015/02/07/let-life-surprise-you-predictability-is-becoming-obsolete/"/>
    <updated>2015-02-07T18:06:13-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/blog/2015/02/07/let-life-surprise-you-predictability-is-becoming-obsolete</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This week was special for many people and hopefully  for you as well. Not because you got excited of  <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2015/02/02/tinder-plus-the-paid-version-featuring-an-undo-button-and-more-arrives-in-u-s-next-month/"><b>news about “Tinder Plus.</b>”</a>
This other moment, when you thought &ldquo;Wow, I didn&rsquo;t expect that to happen. It should happen way more often!&rdquo;</p>

<p>There are more of this moments than we tend to realize.  <a href="http://lifehacker.com/carry-a-surprise-journal-to-find-areas-for-self-impro-1638467349"><b>Sometimes it just needs a little reminder.</b></a></p>

<p style="text-align:center">
<img src="/images/post/launch-75.png" title="center" >
</p>


<!-- more -->


<p>Somehow you found your way to this blog. Maybe on purpose or maybe by accident. No matter how, it seems like you are as passionate about people, socializing and technology as we are.</p>

<p>Technology has become a great tool for those, who love people. There are many new ways for those who are passionate about getting in touch with new spirits. Anyway it is <a href="http://www.entrepreneur.com/article/236752"><b>hard to substitute the energy you feel when you get in touch with people.</b></a></p>

<p>Sometimes the way we are using technology is drifting away from the original purpose. Everyone knows the point when you start realizing that some of your routines shifted from supporting real life encounters to using technology for its own sake.</p>

<p>Instead of enjoying the thrill of possible rejection, we use technology to find a match before meeting.</p>

<p>Instead of planing a trip, we use technology to find the quickest route.</p>

<p>Instead of looking forward to meetings, we use technology to optimize our schedule.</p>

<p>The most beautiful moments of socializing don’t happen on purpose.</p>

<p>It’s this moment when you’ve been heavily procrastinating to call an old friend and just stumble into him at the small café you haven&rsquo;t been to for a year.</p>

<p>It’s this moment when you meet a business partner at a concert and discover that both of you fell in love with the same punk band twenty years ago.</p>

<p>It’s this moment when you start talking to a stranger in a hostel and end up spending a whole weekend together discovering a new city.</p>

<p>Those are the moments when you start realizing that it’s not always about optimizing your day. Often it&rsquo;s the <a href="https://www.ted.com/talks/charlie_todd_the_shared_experience_of_absurdity"><b>spontaneous encounters that bring  more value to your life.</b></a></p>

<p>Now ask yourself two questions: &ldquo;Was there a moment this week, I hope to remember in the future? Did this moment happen exactly the way I pictured it last week?&rdquo;</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s time to put the spotlight on people again and let technology help you encounter more of those spontaneous moments. Reflect about this topic on your preferred channel with the hashtag #liveisspontan (no feeds yet, can be our thing) and get in touch with us to create more of this moments together.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
