<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: als | Socialeyes Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/blog/categories/als/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-03-19T04:47:15-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Socialeyes]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What is the ALS Ice Bucket Challenge?]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/blog/2014/08/18/what-is-the-als-ice-bucket-challenge/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-18T12:05:56-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/blog/2014/08/18/what-is-the-als-ice-bucket-challenge</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you have not seen this viral and social game already, you will certainly see one in the near future. A friend of yours appears in a video saying that he/she was nominated for ALS by this and that person, and nominates a couple of other people to do the same. And they are given 24 hours to complete the task. Then what? A bucket of iced water is being poured down over the head. It is funny, it is viral and it also benefits society. It is genius!</p>

<h2>WHY ALS?</h2>

<p>ALS is a disease that gradually damages nerve cells that control muscles. In other words, it makes people lose control over their muscles, meaning they slowly lose the ability to walk, speak, eat and breath. People with ALS have a life expectancy of 2 to 5 years. The serious thing here is that there’s no treatment and the only approved drug buys just a little bit more time. The whole purpose of this challenge is to raise awareness (which is right on!) and raise money for ALS. As of last week, the ALS association received $4 million of charity within the past month. Obviously things got a bit wilder once Facebook’s Mark Zuckerberg got nominated to do the ALS Ice Bucket Challenge. The amount of charity collected for the week after Mark’s nomination video is not revealed yet but obviously it created a huge traction for the ALS Ice Bucket Challenge.</p>

<h2>WHY ICE BUCKET?</h2>

<p>It makes sense. It is summer time (at least for most of the people), it is a bit challenging and anyone use a bit refreshment on these hot summer days. Besides it is funny to see people dumping iced water over their heads.</p>

<h2>WHAT IS THE CHALLENGE?</h2>

<p>Either dump the bucket of iced water over the head, or donate $100 to ALS association.</p>

<h2>WHO HAS DONE IT?</h2>

<p>There are lots of celebrities who have been challenged and have accepted. Among the famous people here are our favorite ALS Ice Bucket Challenge videos:</p>

<h3>Mark Zuckerberg</h3>

<p><div class="embed-video-container"><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/6TTpXKFBkjk" width="854" height="480" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></p>

<h3>Bill Gates</h3>

<p><div class="embed-video-container"><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/XS6ysDFTbLU" width="854" height="480" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></p>

<h3>Jimmy Fallon with Rob Riggle, Horatio Sanz, Steve Higgins, The Roots</h3>

<p><div class="embed-video-container"><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/b_kdke345NQ" width="854" height="480" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></p>

<h3>Justin Timberlake</h3>

<p><div class="embed-video-container"><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/-4smHMO1Crg" width="854" height="480" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
