<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: germany | Socialeyes Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/blog/categories/germany/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-02-07T21:12:26-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Socialeyes]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[World Cup Champions 2014]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/blog/2014/07/13/world-cup-champions-2014/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-13T20:09:45-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/blog/2014/07/13/world-cup-champions-2014</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It’s been one of the most entertaining World Cup tournaments in history. In the final we had two great sides. Germany against Argentina. Argentina did very good defensive work throughout the World Cup 2014. They came all the way to the final in this tournament hosted by their arch rivals. Winning the title could mean a lot more than just a championship for the Argentinians. Germans put out an excellent team performance in World Cup 2014 and deserved the Cup all the way.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p><img src="/images/post/germany2014.jpg"></p>

<p>Although there was much challenge and competition in the final, it would not be a fair assessment to say that the final game was a thrilling one. It ended in extra time by the spectacular half volley of Mario Gotze.</p>

<p>Neuer, the German goalkeeper was awarded the Golden Glove for his outstanding performance in World Cup 2014. Lionel Messi was awarded the Golden Ball. Let’s confess it, we all love Lionel Messi so much that even though his performances were behind some of the other names in the tournament like any German player, or Argentinian Garay, or Colombian James Rodriguez, we give him the award.</p>

<p>Let us not forget that despite the fact that Brazilian fans are pretty much disheartened by their performance in World Cup 2014, they hosted an amazing tournament. Let us also not forget that they finished in top 4. One of the highlights of the tournament will surely be their historical defeat by Germans with a unforgettable score of 7-1. For some, this score put the actual final in its shade.</p>

<p>We have had Portugal with Cristiano Ronaldo, Argentina with Lionel Messi, Netherlands with Arjen Robben, Brazil with Neymar… But the fact remains the same. Football, as we know it, is a team sport and Germany showed this to any football fan around the world. Let us all celebrate the winners and not forget that a world with sports is way more fun and exciting. Cheers All!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A World Cup Final Before The Actual World Cup Final]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/blog/2014/07/10/a-world-cup-final-before-the-actual-world-cup-final/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-10T03:24:57-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/blog/2014/07/10/a-world-cup-final-before-the-actual-world-cup-final</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It&rsquo;s almost the World Cup Final day. Yet the people talk about only one game. The epic defeat of Brazil by Germany. Surely millions of sports fans had not been expecting the 6 goal difference football show the other day. And it literally broke the hearts of the millions of Brazilian sports fans who were quite eager to see the final of the World Cup which was hosted by the Brazilians themselves. Here is a funny video that summarizes the whole semifinal defeat in ten seconds.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p><div class="embed-video-container"><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/gIUDNtb6qY0" width="854" height="480" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></p>

<p>We, the Socialeyes Team loved this video! The soundtrack playing the famous &ldquo;Brazil&rdquo; song, which is interrupted with a gigantic beer glass that has German flag on it that crushes the cocktail glass that represents Brazil.</p>

<p>Obviously this game has already put the actual final in its shade. Now that we have Argentina matched up with Germany in the World Cup Final, fans will be expecting another goal show from the German Panzers. On the other hand, the host fans, will watch this World Cup Final with fear, hoping that their fierce rivals Argentina does not end up lifting up the World Cup. From another point of view, surely the streets of Buenos Aires will watch a very exciting World Cup Final hoping that they end up becoming the champions of the World Cup in Brazil.</p>

<p>So the question here is: will we see another video of Argentinian Wine Glass smashed by the Gigantic German Glass, or will Lionel Messi&rsquo;s Argentina bring the title home by making their fans proud on this special World Cup Final.</p>

<p>Now we know that many fans worldwide are expecting to see their idol, Lionel Messi to lift the World Cup, making him a true football legend and take his place in history. On the other hand, we have a very strong and on form German team that displays excellence in team play.</p>

<p>All we know that on Sunday night, millions of people all across the globe will watch the World Cup Final without the blink of an eye. And us, as the Socialeyes Team will light up our barbeque, have our favorite beers in our hands and enjoy this most entertaining sports event with our beloved fans.
You think the Germans will win? Or is it going to be the night for Argentinian Tango.</p>

<p>Send us what you think support[at]socialeyesapp.com</p>

<p>Or simply tweet us @socialeyesapp</p>

<p>Or socialize with us on Facebook <a href="https://www.facebook.com/pages/Socialeyes/360111724123590">https://www.facebook.com/pages/Socialeyes/360111724123590</a></p>

<p>Goallll!!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
