<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: ios 8 | Socialeyes Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/blog/categories/ios-8/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-09-18T03:30:42-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Socialeyes]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sour Apple]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/blog/2014/09/18/sour-apple/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-18T03:23:32-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.socialeyesapp.com/blog/2014/09/18/sour-apple</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Apple introduced iPhone 6 and launched its iOS 8 platform in the recent days. Let us take a look at how Apple has made its fans upset in many ways.</p>

<p>iPhone 6 and iPhone 6 Plus: Remember the times when Apple was the pioneer in smart devices? Steve and his crew would create, the rest would just follow. The first thing we have seen was that this changed.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>It is not very hard to see that Apple has followed the footsteps of its competitor, Samsung with its new products. One can easily see this only by looking at the phones. Besides we were unable to see any other cool features that makes the Apple fans go “wow”. Apart from the screen size changes and iOS 8, I can hardly see that Apple may keep its momentum as it was in the past. Good luck with iPhone 6 when competing with Samsung.</p>

<p style="text-align:center">
<img src="/images/post/steve_jobs_1.jpg" title="right" >
<br />
<em>Steve Jobs, coding.</em>
</p>


<p>Apple Watch: We have to admit, it is a cool design. Will it be practical to use it? It is a question mark for all of us. I guess we’ll have to wait for 2015 for the release date. One thing for sure though, again we see that Apple has followed the footsteps of its competitors.</p>

<p>iOS 8: Remember the time when Apple announced that iOS 7 was going to be the biggest change for Apple users? Well it was right on. People complained about some of the downsides of iOS 7 (especially iPhone 4 users) but it was good innovation. However there have been some small mistakes that created prejudice in the minds of Apple fans. Why make it 5.7 GB? This is almost half the memory for many iPhone users. If the users do not have memory for downloading apps, taking photos, recording videos, what is iOS 8 good for then? As if Apple leave such small memory to its users for other actions, why include a U2 album within the app? Do you know if your users like it? Perhaps there are people that do not like U2?</p>

<p>The battery problem for the iPhone devices seems to remain the same. Which is quite disappointing given the fact that 9 out of 10 iPhone users list battery problem as their biggest problem with the device.</p>

<p>Oh Steve, we missed you already. Rest in peace.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
